starware.com 2008-12-18

# Starware Toolbar Privacy Policy

**STARWARE TOOLBAR PRIVACY POLICY**

At Starware we work hard to deliver the best custom web tools at no cost to our users while maintaining the most professional service standards.

Starware's principle revenue is earned through search tools downloaded with our toolbar. Sites pay to get certain placement within keyword search results. If users find those relevant results attractive and click through to the page, the advertiser pays the search partner for the click and we share in that revenue. Our search tools are designed to be as helpful to the user as possible while driving revenue for better Starware products in the future.

Your happiness with our software is very important to us and we only hope to include you as one of our millions of satisfied users. 

**POLICY OVERVIEW**

We want you to feel comfortable downloading and using our products. We understand that your trust in us depends on us respecting your privacy and safeguarding information we may access.

We encourage anyone using this software (the "Starware Toolbar") to make educated decisions about their online practices. To help them do so, this Privacy Policy details the important information that will help answer any questions regarding personal privacy in relation to our Starware Toolbar. Also, this Privacy Policy is incorporated with and subject to the Starware [Terms of Use](http://www.starware.com/4.5/terms.php).

**Practices**

  * Our software is installed only with the user's permission.
  * We do not collect or track personal information.
  * We design & control all our own distribution channels, always control the download of our own products and, with the exception of Screensavers.com, do not allow third parties to bundle our software.
  * We do not bundle third party software.
  * We allow you to disable advertising features that you feel are not valuable.
  * We make it easy for you to uninstall our software through the standard Add/Remove interface. If you don't like it, simply uninstall it.
  * We put our brand on our products and provide you with links to our customer service department.
  * We are proud of our software and our business and will always tell you what we do.

**Data Collection**

When this Privacy Policy uses the term "personal information," we mean information that might help identify a particular individual, such as the individual's name, postal address, e-mail address, and telephone number.

We do not collect personal information, with perhaps the exception of your zip code, which you may or may not choose to provide us; this would be necessary to effectively power our weather product and deliver your local forecast.

We need to collect some non-personal data to power our products and monitor our performance. Here is exactly what we do and don't do:

  * We do not send or collect any information that can personally identify a user.
  * We do offer to set your homepage to www.mystarware.com; if you do not want to change your homepage simply uncheck the respective selection in the dialog box presented during installation.
  * We do collect information that is already available to every website you visit. Examples include browser version, language and other browser and connection information.
  * We use a unique ID in order to know how many people use our products. This ID is not personally identifying; it is a completely random number.
  * We do send a log once per day that tells us how many users are installed.
  * We do collect data at our search and travel sites. This is needed to monitor our business performance. This data does not contain any personally identifying information.
  * We do not and will not sell or distribute any data collected from the user.
  * We do share aggregated information with others. Examples of this include how many users clicked on a particular paid listing in a search result.
  * We do send your search terms and your respective clicks to our "Related Search" server and use that data in the aggregate to provide better related search products.
  * We do take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data.

**Search & Default Settings**

When you download the Starware Toolbar you get a variety of useful tools and features. In exchange, our users drive revenue for us by clicking search results delivered in response to the user's own search queries. Most of our searches are generated through the use of our toolbar. Other search features are activated by modification of default Internet Explorer browser settings. These default settings originally display results to the benefit of Microsoft, using MSN listings. After installing the Starware Toolbar, these search results will be delivered by Starware instead; examples of this include results from the Internet Explorer search box, Error Search and searches conducted through the address bar. In addition, we display related search suggestions in a bottom pain in response to any search engine query. These products perform well, as they can be very handy.

Should the user find any of these tools unnecessary or undesirable they can easily be disabled through our "Preferences" menu.

**Disable & Removal**

You are clearly given the choice to opt out of any of our search utilities outlined in the previous section during the install process. You may also disable these utilities and settings through our Preference settings by clicking the Starware icon on the far left of the toolbar and choosing "Preferences." This allows you to turn off features you don't like and keep those you do.

Uninstall is simple. Go to your Start Menu>Control Panel>Add/Remove Programs. When you have the Add/Remove Control Panel open, scroll down the list of installed programs until you see "Starware." Select it by clicking and then choose "Change/Remove." It should remove the program all together. If you still see the toolbar on your desktop, or any other Starware files remaining on your hard drive, please contact us at [Customer Support](http://www.starware.com/4.5/support.php).

**Cookies**

You download our cookies when you visit our sites and download our software. Our cookies are stored on your hard drive and communicate with our servers only when you are visiting our websites/search sites or using the Starware Toolbar, including any of its search features or tools.

We use cookies (a) to hold user specific data and information that maintain your personal settings and allow us to deliver more relevant content and information; (b) to determine where you got our software in order to monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (c) to monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and (e) to track your status as a new or existing user (i.e. via a "heartbeat log" sent once a day upon launch of IE).

Our cookies are absolutely harmless but they may be disable through Internet Explorer settings should you wish to do so.

**Updating**

Our product is dynamic in much the same way as a web page. Some files reside on the user's local machine, some reside on our servers. Bug fixes and new features may be added to the product without notice. Advance permission to do so may be important if we find a bug that could adversely affect your computer. Should any new product, feature or software modification require us to modify our privacy policy will make such requirements known to the user and allow the user to block the data or disable the product. Otherwise updates will be made without notice to the user.

**Links**

The URLs displayed as search results or other sites linked to by us on the toolbar or otherwise are developed by people over whom Starware exercises no authority. These other sites may place their own cookies on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information without our knowledge or control. Starware is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such websites and under no circumstances shall Starware be liable for any such third party's actions or uses of data.

**Changes to this Policy**

  * Please note this Privacy Policy is subject to change. Our current privacy policy will always be made available at this page. The policy version will be noted at the bottom of the page and previous versions will be made available to review upon request.
  * This Privacy Policy shall not be construed as preventing us from complying with any court order, court authorized discovery, or agency authorized discovery of any information we may have access to. 
  * This Privacy Policy does not provide you with any remedy or cause of action against us in the event that we provide any information we can access, including information relating to your use of Starware software, to a third-party or agency in compliance with any Starware legal obligation, which shall be determined at our sole discretion. 

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Starware Privacy Policy or its implementation please contact us: 

Starware  
Attention: Chief Privacy Officer  
143 Varick Street  
New York, NY 10013  

NEED MORE INFO? If there are any terms in this policy you don't understand, visit [www.webopedia.com](http://www.webopedia.com/). If you would like to learn more about how to protect your privacy online, check out the following online resources:

Updated June 14, 2007
